ANDREW LEACH

Edmonton, AB

+1 780-217-2453

@andrew_leach

leach.andrew@gmail.com

leach-econ



leachandrew



aleach.ca/charts

Economist. Data Scientist. Policy Analyst. Academic leader.

I am an energy and environmental economist and currently Associate Professor at the University of Alberta, where I also direct the CABREE energy research centre and an interdisciplinary research group under the Future Energy Systems Signature Area. My academic research spans energy and environmental economics with a focus on climate change policies and the law. I am also an avid data scientist, exploring ways to extract, summarize, and visualize energy and environmental measures and economic indicators. I am a prolific writer, with over 200 bylines in major Canadian media outlets.

EXPERIENCE

2011 - present Associate Professor, Alberta School of Business, University of Alberta

Faculty member in the Natural Resources, Energy and Environment group, Academic Director of

CABREE Research Centre, and Future Energy Systems grant holder.

2020 - present Sessional Instructor, Faculty of Law, University of Alberta

Developed and delivered a course on environmental law and policy.

Economics and Policy Consultant, 2006 - present

Environmental policy development and evaluation. Policy advisor to federal and provincial govern-

ments. Expert witness on energy, economic, and regulatory files.

2006 - 2011 Assistant Professor, Alberta School of Business, University of Alberta

Faculty member in the Natural Resources, Energy and Environment group.

2003 - 2006 Assistant Professor/Professeur Adjoint, HEC Montréal

Faculty member in the Institute of Applied Economics.

EDUCATION

2019 - 2020 LLM (Constitutional Law), University of Alberta

Thesis examined the constitutional anchors for climate change policies under the POGG, Trade and

Commerce, and Criminal Law powers of the federal government.

1999 - 2003 Ph.D. (Economics), Queen's University

Thesis focussed on applying numerical methods to examine the economics of climate change

policy, including distributional issues and the impacts of uncertainty and learning on optimal policy.

1998 - 1999 MA (Economics), University of Guelph

Focus on environmental, resource, and labour economics.

1994 - 1998 B.Sc. (Environmental Science), University of Guelph Major: Environmental Economics and Policy.

WORK PRODUCT

Publications Academic Publications aleach.ca/publications

An on-line archive of my academic publications.

Data Data and visualization project archive aleach.ca/projects

Visualization A public archive of data aggregation, collection and visualization tools.

Opinion **Opinion Archive** aleach.ca/opinion

An archive of my public writing, Parliamentary Committee testimony and more.

LANGUAGES HOBBIES NON PROFIT

English - native I am an avid cyclist, occasional runner, French - proficient downhill and cross-country skier, hockey

player, and hobbyist woodworker.

Board of Directors, REACH Edmonton and Edmonton Juventus Cycling Club. Past Board Member, River Valley Alliance and Economic Society of Northern Alberta.